<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE SerialKiller SYSTEM "index.dtd">
<shahin>
<title scr="/images/header.jpg">Infamous Serial Killenfamous Serial Killers</title>
	<networks>
		<network scr="/images/facebook.png" alt="facebookicon" href="http://www.facebook.com/Rajaei.shahin">facebook</network>
		<network scr="/images/linkedin.png" alt="linkedinIcon" href="http://linkedin.com/in/shahin-rajaei-251469168">Linkedin</network>
		<network scr="/images/twitter.png" alt="twitterIcon" href="https://twitter.com/vilsoon10">twitter</network>
		<network scr="images/gmail.png" alt="linkedinIcon" href="shahin.rajaei@etu.univ-poitiers.fr">Gmail</network>
	</networks>
<head>Infamous murderer Jack the Ripper killed at least five London female
          prostitutes in 1888. Never captured, his identity is one of English's
          most famous unsolved mysteries.
	</head>
	<description>
		<h2>Who Was Jack the Ripper?</h2>
        <p>
          From August 7 to September 10 in 1888, "Jack the Ripper" terrorized
          the Whitechapel district in London's East End. He killed at least five
          prostitutes and mutilated their bodies in an unusual manner,
          indicating that the killer had a knowledge of human anatomy. Jack the
          Ripper was never captured, and remains one of England's, and the
          world's, most infamous criminals.
        </p>
        <h2>Suspects and Victims</h2>
        <p>
          Known for committing gruesome murders from August 7 to September 10 in
          1888, "Jack the Ripper" — a moniker for the notorious serial killer,
          who was never identified — remains one of England's, and the world's,
          most infamous criminals. The culprit responsible for the murders of
          five prostitutes—all took place within a mile of each other, and
          involved the districts of Whitechapel, Spitalfields, Aldgate and the
          City of London—in London's East End in the autumn of 1888 was never
          apprehended. Despite countless investigations claiming definitive
          evidence of the brutal killer's identity, his name and motive are
          still unknown. The moniker "Jack the Ripper" originates from a letter
          written by someone who claimed to be the Whitechapel butcher,
          published at the time of the attacks. Adding to the mystery of the
          affair is the fact that several letters were sent by the killer to the
          London Metropolitan Police Service, also known as the Scotland Yard,
          taunting officers about his gruesome activities and speculating on
          murders to come. Various theories about Jack the Ripper's identity
          have been produced over the past several decades, which include claims
          accusing the famous Victorian painter Walter Sickert, a Polish migrant
          and even the grandson of Queen Victoria. Since 1888, more than 100
          suspects have been named, contributing to widespread folklore and
          ghoulish entertainment surrounding the mystery. In the late 1800s,
          London's East End was a place that was viewed by citizens with either
          compassion or utter contempt. Despite being an area where skilled
          immigrants, mainly Jews and Russians, came to start a new life and
          start businesses, the district was notorious for squalor, violence and
          crime. Prostitution was only illegal if the practice caused a public
          disturbance, and thousands of brothels and low-rent lodging houses
          provided sexual services during the late 19th century. At that time,
          the death or murder of a working girl was rarely reported in the press
          or discussed within polite society. The reality was that "ladies of
          the night" were subject to physical attacks, which sometimes resulted
          in death. Among these common violent crimes was the attack of English
          prostitute Emma Smith, who was beaten and raped with an object by four
          men. Smith, who later died of peritonitis, is remembered as one of
          many unfortunate female victims who were killed by gangs demanding
          protection money. However, the series of killings that began in August
          1888 stood out from other violent crime of the time: They were marked
          by sadistic butchery, suggesting a mind more sociopathic and hateful
          than most citizens could comprehend. Jack the Ripper didn't just snuff
          out life with a knife, he mutilated and humiliated women, and his
          crimes seemed to portray an abhorrence for the entire female gender.
          When Jack the Ripper's murders suddenly stopped, in the fall of 1888,
          London citizens wanted answers that would not come, even more than a
          century later. The ongoing case—which has spawned an industry of
          books, films, TV series and historical tours—has met with a number of
          hindrances, including lack of evidence, a gamut of misinformation and
          false testimony, and tight regulations by the Scotland Yard. Jack the
          Ripper has been the topic of news stories for more than 130 years, and
          will likely continue to be for decades to come.
        </p>
        <h2>In Recent Years</h2>
        <p>
          In 2011, British detective Trevor Marriott, who had long been
          investigating the Jack the Ripper murders, made headlines when he was
          denied access to uncensored documents surrounding the case by the
          Metropolitan Police. According to a 2011 ABC News article, London
          officers refused to give Marriott the files because they include
          protected information about police informants, thereby potentially
          dissuading testimony by modern-day informants. In 2014, author and
          amateur sleuth Russell Edwards claimed to have determined the identity
          of Jack the Ripper by DNA results obtained from a shawl belonging to
          one of the victims, Catherine Eddowes. Edwards asserted the evidence
          pointed to Aaron Kosminski, a Polish immigrant and one of the prime
          suspects in the grisly murders. The topic resurfaced when two
          biochemists published the results of their tests on the shawl in a
          March 2019 edition of Journal of Forensic Sciences, again fingering
          Kosminski as a likely match. That finding was quickly disputed by
          geneticists who challenged the methodology used and insisted that the
          shawl had been contaminated by inappropriate handling.
        </p>
		<QUICKfacts src="./images/jack.jpg"/>
          <name>Jack the Ripper</name>
          <AKA>Jack the Ripper</AKA>
	</description>
	<footer src="./images/uniLogo.png" alt="uniLogo">About me: My name is Shahin Rajaei, I am 25 years old and I am
          studying medicine at the University of Poitiers. I was born in Iran
          and in high school I was interested in web design with the help of my
          friends, but I decided to change my life path and come to France.
	</Footnote>
	<background src="./images/bcg.jpg"/>
</shahin>